<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>SQL Server Diaries</title>
    
    
    <description>A personal take on SQL Server solutions</description>
    
    <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Holding On</title>
        <description>
          
          Some of my blog posts are available in an almost original format on the Internet Archive: Wayback Machine

        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2013/03/01/holding-on/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2013/03/01/holding-on/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog Offline</title>
        <description>
          
          After two years of writing, my (previous…) hosting provider unfortunately managed to lose all my articles; they couldn’t even recover the configuration from their own backup! In time I did recover most of the content, and will re-post all articles in due course. I hope to be back online soon,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2013/02/01/blog-offline/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2013/02/01/blog-offline/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deploy or Migrate a Database using Scripts - part 1</title>
        <description>
          
          A database migration is always a headache for DBAs.  There are different approaches one may take, some being simpler than others. A couple of weeks ago, in the Migrate Databases Using Backup-Restore article, I explained how a database migration can be carried out effortlessly and with minimal downtime.  This is...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2012/12/21/deploy-or-migrate-a-database-using-scripts-part-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2012/12/21/deploy-or-migrate-a-database-using-scripts-part-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Documenting the Owner of a Generic Database User</title>
        <description>
          
          A developer asked about whether it was possible to store additional tags to identify the owner of a generic login or generic database user.  The below solution can be used to store this information and also offers further possibilities. Starting from SQL Server 2000, databases allow for the addition of custom...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/04/30/documenting-the-owner-of-a-generic-database-user/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/04/30/documenting-the-owner-of-a-generic-database-user/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Compare the Contents (data) of Two Tables</title>
        <description>
          
          An application developer asked me if there was an option in SQL Server to compare the contents/data of two tables without having to create a custom application.  There are various third party tools that can achieve this target however SQL Server comes with an out-of-the-box solution. The SQL Server Replication...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/04/23/compare-the-contents-data-of-two-tables/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/04/23/compare-the-contents-data-of-two-tables/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Use the Forfiles Utility to Delete Old Database Backup Files</title>
        <description>
          
          I came across a tool that some might find useful.  The Forfiles on Microsoft Technet utility (forfiles.exe) is preinstalled with Windows Server 2003 and later.  Forfiles enables batch processing of files.  One use of this utility would be to delete old backup files to remove dependencies on items such as...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/04/16/use-the-forfiles-utility-to-delete-old-database-backup-files/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/04/16/use-the-forfiles-utility-to-delete-old-database-backup-files/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using GUIDs as Primary Keys, or not</title>
        <description>
          
          Also known as Globally Unique Identifiers, GUID values consist of a string of alphanumeric values which in principle should be unique across all machines of the network.  GUID values are stored in a database table using the uniqueidentifier (Transact-SQL) data type and requires 16 bytes of storage space per row....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/04/09/using-guids-as-primary-keys-or-not/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/04/09/using-guids-as-primary-keys-or-not/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SQL Server Connection Strings, Unique Application DNS and Listening Ports</title>
        <description>
          
          Managing SQL Server applications can be a bit tricky, especially in an enterprise scenario with tens or hundreds of applications deployed for a large user-base across geographically dispersed locations.  With a bit of planning, events such as database migrations, DBMS upgrade, or server virtualisation to name a few, can be...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/04/02/sql-server-connection-strings-unique-application-dns-and-listening-ports/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/04/02/sql-server-connection-strings-unique-application-dns-and-listening-ports/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Create a Database Mail profile in 4 Steps (or less)</title>
        <description>
          
          Database Mail provides functionality to send email using T-SQL and is the successor to SQL Server 2000’s SQL Mail. Although SQL Mail is still available in SQL Server 2005, it is provided for backward compatibility only and the Books Online reccomend that Database Mail is used instead. Configuring Database Mail...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/03/26/create-a-database-mail-profile-in-4-steps-or-less/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/03/26/create-a-database-mail-profile-in-4-steps-or-less/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Script Logins from Database Users</title>
        <description>
          
          When performing a database migration from one SQL Server instance to another, the DBA has to transfer all logins which have access to the database.  The transfer will only be successful if the logins retain the same passwords to reduce the impact on the end users, and more specifically, the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/03/19/script-logins-from-database-users/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/03/19/script-logins-from-database-users/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Generate Lottery Ticket Combinations</title>
        <description>
          
          In Malta, the Super 5 lottery prize has always been considered the peak of winnings by the Maltese.  So much so that it has become part of the day-to-day language when referring to good luck (I feel I just won the Super 5!).  As a challenge, I thought of how...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/03/12/generate-lottery-ticket-combinations/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/03/12/generate-lottery-ticket-combinations/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Addressing a 'login failed' (Error 18452) error message in SQL Server 2005</title>
        <description>
          
          An excellent article posted by Il-Sung Lee (Program Manager, SQL Server Protocols) at Understanding “login failed” (Error 18456) error messages in SQL Server 2005 describes the various error message severity levels. Recently a user who uses an application which connects to an SQL Server 2005 instance using Windows Authentication from...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/03/05/addressing-a-login-failed-error-18452-error-message-in-sql-server-2005/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/03/05/addressing-a-login-failed-error-18452-error-message-in-sql-server-2005/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Run SQL Server Agent Jobs with Alternate Credentials</title>
        <description>
          
          According to the Selecting an Account for the SQL Server Agent Service, the SQL Server Agent service account should be able to authenticate with the instance and also be a memeber of the sysadmin fixed server role. Agent jobs are usually created by a DBA and by default will execute...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/02/26/run-sql-server-agent-jobs-with-alternate-credentials/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/02/26/run-sql-server-agent-jobs-with-alternate-credentials/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Send SQL Server Agent Job log file by Email</title>
        <description>
          
          When creating an SQL Server Agent job with one or more steps, each step can be configured to write the query output to a log file.  If the job failes, such a log can assist a DBA identify the cause of the failure.  That is, if the log is still...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/02/19/send-sql-server-agent-job-log-by-email/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/02/19/send-sql-server-agent-job-log-by-email/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Generating a Database Data Dictionary</title>
        <description>
          
          Accurate documentation is paramount for any system. Unfotunately, when developing a database we sometimes tend to overlook this particular document. A data dictionary shows metadata about your database. This information can be generated from the DBMS itself using the INFORMATION_SCHEMA compatibility views. Information such as the list of tables, table...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/02/12/generating-a-database-data-dictionary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/02/12/generating-a-database-data-dictionary/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Database Upgrade from SQL Server 7</title>
        <description>
          
          When migrating databases from SQL Server 7 or 2000 to SQL Server 2005/2008 the steps can be summarised as follows: Migrate all logins (including passwords) accessing the database Disallow all connections to the database by restricting access only to SYSADMIN’s Back up the database and copy the backup file (or...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/02/05/database-upgrade-from-sql-server-7/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/02/05/database-upgrade-from-sql-server-7/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Header for Database Code Objects</title>
        <description>
          
          Stored procedures and functions allow for the implementation of groups of data manipulation language (DML) statements as database objects.  Besides each code block having the relevant comments to facilitate other parties’ understanding of the same code blocks (amongst other reasons), a good coding practice is that some information about the object...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/01/29/header-for-database-code-objects/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/01/29/header-for-database-code-objects/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SSIS error: 'buffer manager cannot create a temporary storage file on any path in the BufferTempStoragePath property'</title>
        <description>
          
          An ETL SSIS package implemented on a test environment was failing occasionally with the error: The buffer manager cannot create a temporary storage file on any path in the BufferTempStoragePath property. There is an incorrect file name or no permission. The package was failing on various occasions when copying binary...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2010/12/30/ssis-buffertempstoragepath-error/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2010/12/30/ssis-buffertempstoragepath-error/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Protecting against SQL Injection attacks</title>
        <description>
          
          In a nutshell, an SQL injection attack is one where malicious code is passed to an instance of SQL Server for parsing and execution through a vulnerable application.  Although most SQL injection attacks can come from the web (having a larger “target audience”) even machines connected to an organisation’s network...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/01/15/protecting-against-sql-injection-attacks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/01/15/protecting-against-sql-injection-attacks/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Date and Time data types</title>
        <description>
          
          Someone asked me why storing datetime values seem to allow a maximum year of 2079. The limit mentioned exists for the SQL Server smalldatetime data type. This is because of the values’ data range supported, accuracy and data size associated with different data types where: Data type Range Accuracy Size...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/01/08/date-and-time-data-types/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/index.php/2011/01/08/date-and-time-data-types/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
